index:	0
title:	web page
desc:	What was I smoking when I created this web page.

body:
<p>
	My (sparky's) main idea when creating this web page was to make it as simple as
	possible while maximizing functionality. Any fancy stuff was added
	only because it didn't conflict with the main ideology.
</p>

<h2>goals</h2>
<dl>
	<dt>must look good in text-based web browser</dt>
	<dd>
		Underlying html is very simple and condensed. There are no
		floating menus, popup menus or narrow columns with additional
		information. This makes it look perfectly in lynx and similar
		web browsers, also all subpages are easily accessible.
	</dd>
	<dt>must look good on small screen</dt>
	<dd>
		Columns are just 620px wide. Screen 800px wide (like those in
		some eeepc) is more than enough.

	</dd>
	<dt>must take advantage of wide screens</dt>
	<dd>
		Horizontal stacking of pages makes them occupy whole screen.
	</dd>
	<dt>must be browsable with only the keyboard</dt>
	<dd>
		Goal very similar to that of text web browser. No popup things
		make it very easy to navigate with just the keyboard.
	</dd>
	<dt>simple pleasant look</dt>
	<dd>
		All surfaces have added a little noise, this makes them look brushed,
		not shiny. Low contrast letters are very pleasing to look at.
		In addition reddish color in links emphasizes grayscale nature of
		the page. This was somewhat influenced by Amiga game
		<a href="http://www.lemonamiga.com/games/details.php?id=828">Perihelion</a>.
	</dd>
	<dt>easy access to subpages</dt>
	<dd>
		Each page serves as menu with links to subpages. It also puts
		links in some context.
	</dd>
	<dt>printable</dt>
	<dd>
		Uses separate CSS for printed media. Condensed html allowed
		to make it look good on paper without much effort.
	</dd>
</dl>

<h2>tools and technology</h2>
<dl>
	<dt>Valid XHTML 1.1</dt>
	<dd>
		Each page is validated using <a href="http://xmlsoft.org/">xmllint</a>
		just before uploading to the server. This way all the pages
		can be served as <tt>text/xml</tt> and take advantage of xml
		extensions.
	</dd>
	<dt>Almost valid CSS 2.1</dt>
	<dd>
		Is uses <tt>::selection</tt> which is part of CSS 3, and
		<tt>::-moz-selection</tt> which does the same but works in
		gecko engine. Other than that there are no browser tricks.
	</dd>
	<dt>JavaScript</dt>
	<dd>
		Tries to adhere to DOM specification as much as possible, but
		some non-portable code was needed as well.
	</dd>
	<dt>Build tools</dt>
	<dd>
		Destination pages are built from sources using my own perl
		contraption, I'd like to use XSLT for this task some day.
		SVN changelogs are built using XSLT style sheet.
	</dd>
	<dt>Server-side scripting</dt>
	<dd>
		Almost all pages are static. Only few of them use PHP.
		Nevertheless a well configured web server is required.
	</dd>
	<dt>Sources</dt>
	<dd>
		All web page sources are managed on
		<a href="http://github.com/sparky/rsget.pl-web">github</a>.
	</dd>
</dl>
