index:	0
title:	about
desc:	Basic information. This section will some day be organized.

body:
<p>
	<strong>rsget.pl</strong> is primarily designed to run on a
	small server on top of your home network. Any hardware capable of
	running perl will do, for me it is <em>AMD K6/2 450MHz with 320MB
		of RAM</em> but even a machine with 1/5 of those specifications
	should be enough.
</p>
<p>
	<strong>rsget.pl</strong> was tested and works as expected on a
	variety of UNIX-like systems, those include Linux, FreeBSD, NetBSD,
	Open Solaris and Mac OS X. There shouldn't be any problem with
	operating systems from UNIX family. Other operating systems, especially
	those which do not handle file paths in same way UNIX does (i.e.
	React OS or Windows, Mac OS) may not be supported.
</p>
<h2>Features</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Perfect for screen session</li>
	<li>Support for many download services</li>
	<li>Supports multiple network interfaces</li>
	<li>Dead interfaces are kicked out (useful with unreliable vpn tunnels)</li>
	<li>Continues partially downloaded files (if download service allows it)</li>
	<li>Incorporates small HTTP server allowing to check the status of downloads,
		and add new links.</li>
	<li>Automatically updates itself from SVN.</li>
</ul>

<h2>TODO</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Write more documentation</li>
	<li>When continuing partially downloaded data start few kb before the end and
		compare old with new.</li>
	<li>Add commands: pause downloads, allow/don't allow captcha, clean done
		downloads, and more</li>
	<li>File group support (first step for multiuser support)</li>
	<li>File priorities and group priorities.</li>
	<li>Selectable temporary directory.</li>
	<li><del>Fix freezing http server - move to separate thread/process ?</del>
		<ins>Should be fixed now.</ins></li>
	<li><del>Fix bugs in http server, and speed it up.</del>
		<ins>Those are list file writer problems.</ins></li>
	<li>Better file writing methods, to allow downloading from multiple sources.</li>
	<li>Backoff if captcha fails too many times; lower uri priority.</li>
	<li>If multi-download problem appears while checking files force check on
		another interface/ip.</li>
	<li><del>Possibility to mark uri as "cannot continue".</del>
		<ins>I'm not sure what I meant by it.</ins></li>
	<li><del>Investigate using user space tunnels (ssh, proxy) to use as
		additional interfaces.</del>
		<ins>Use http proxy or socks as:
		<tt>eth0, http=somehost.com:8080, socks5=localhost:9999</tt></ins></li>
	<li>Download rate limits. Soft limit - don't start another downloads if
		rate limit exceeded. Hard limit - don't allow download speeds
		over specified value.</li>

</ul>

<h2>Planned features</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Multiuser support (may require major changes in the code).</li>
	<li>XML-RPC (or similar) to allow writing GUIs.</li>
	<li>Use SQL for storing links and other data. This should speed things up.
		At least SQLite 3, PostgreSQL and MySQL will be supported to allow
		user chose hers/his favourite.</li>
	<li>Premium accounts support and premium plugins.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Wishful thinking</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Squid and iptables integration. To disallow users accessing
		download sites directly.</li>
	<li>File uploading.</li>
	<li>Download list sharing between daemons running on different hosts.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Not TODO</h2>
<ul>
	<li>Lower memory footprint. -- I have done what I could,
		if it still is to much for your device try curl library with http
		support only (disable https, ftp and others).</li>
	<li>I am thinking about C version of the program with getters written in
		Lua, or some other minimal scripting language. It would enable it
		to run on even the smallest devices. -- Unless someone generously
		sponsors development of that version I will continue work on
		perl version only.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Command-line options</h2>
<pre>For full list of command-line options check: rsget.pl --help. All those options
may also be set in config file ( $HOME/.rsget.pl/config ). Check 'README.config'
file for example config.
Each option requires a value, which may be specified immediately after '=' sign,
or as next argument. Underscores may be replaced with dashes.
Following command-line declarations are equivalent:
 --use_svn=update
 --use-svn=update
 --use_svn update
 --use-svn update
</pre>
